Vinay Siddeshwar

Full Stack Java Developer

My experience provides me the opportunity to work on roles which invloves proficiency in software development life cycle. Reputation for effective team work, strong organizational techniques and oral communication. A quick lerner with 1.5 years of experience in fast-paced envirornment and have an optimistic attitude towards problem solving.



vinysiddeshwar@gmail.com



8904439389



🤔 Bengaluru, India



vinysiddeshwar.github.io/mysite/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer **GE Healthcare**

01/2023 - 08/2023

Clinical Viewer - Real Time Patient Health Data Monitoring System

- Application Development & Defect Fixes.
- Implement Client Requirements.
- Define solution for the backlog(s) scoped for the Sprint and present the same to Tech Lead for review and approval. Incorporate feedback given.
- Integrate unit test and Integration test cases to develop a reliable application.
- Generate SonarQube reports for code quality and worked on code optimization.
- POC's done for R & D work.

Software Engineer. Pratian Technologies

06/2022 - Present

JobCheck-Portal where jobseekers can apply for gig, white collar and blue collar

- Requirements Understanding and interaction with BA.
- Define solution for the backlog(s) scoped for the Sprint and present the same to Tech Lead for review and approval. Incorporate feedback given.
- Implement the Microservices architecture for the requirements scoped.
- Worked on AWS cognito to add user sign-up and authentication to mobile and web apps.
- Work and Test APIs using Swagger and Postman respectively. Write Queries in MySQL for data access and updates.
- Generate SonarQube reports for code quality and worked on code optimization.
- Write Unit Tests across positive, negative scenario using Junit/Mockito.

EDUCATION

PES institute of Technology and Management. Shivamogga.

2015 - 2021

6.7 CGPA

Courses

 Computer Science and Engineering

SAV Composite PU College.

Bhadravathi.

2013 - 2015 85.66%

SKILLS

Core java MySQL Restful Services AWS Cognito **GIT & SCM** TypeScript RabbitMQ

ACADEMIC PROJECT

Image Encryption System Using 3D Chaotic Maps.

Description: In this project, Chaos based technique using two 3DChaotic maps is presented for encrypting the images and enhancing the security.

INTERNSHIP

Tribit Technology (01/2020 - 03/2020)

Bank Management System.

Description: A web based application to virtualize transactions in banking system.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Won several prizes in cultural and sports activities at school level.

Won prizes in sports at school level.

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Kannada

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Hindi

Limited Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Travelling

Motorcyclist

Sports